Rebecca Adamson Papers, 1979-2007
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES
  - "Native Americans in the 21st Century" television series 2000 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - The Natural Step
    - General 1996-98, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Proposals 1995 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting packet 1 Nov 1996 (Box 35, Folder 5-7)
  - Network of East-West Women 1991-92 (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
  - The Philanthropic Initiative, Advisory Board 1995-98 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Positive Futures Network 1999 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - President's Council on Sustainable Development, Economic Development and Jobs Working Group: Task Force on Sustainable Communities (Box 35)
    - Jul 1994 (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
    - Aug 1994-95, undated (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation
    - General 1992-95 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Healthy Nations Program Advisory Committee
      - Cheyenne River Sioux 1995 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Eastern Band of Cherokee proposal 1995 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Warm Springs Healthy Nations Project 1995 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Substance Abuse Policy Research Program 1995 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - St. Francis Indian School, St. Francis, South Dakota 1980 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Sea Change, Board of Advisors 2000-01 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Seventh Generation Fund for Indian Development
    - General
      - 1977, 1984-Mar 1986 (Box 36, Folder 10-12)
      - Apr 1986-90, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-8)
    - Annual reports 1982-87 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Conference, "Investing in Our People and Land: Community and Land-Based Economic Development" Sep 1986 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Social Venture Network 1997-2000 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - State of the World Forum 1995, 1997, 2000-01 (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - "To Our Credit," television program 1994-95 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Tom's of Maine, Board of Directors 2000 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - United Nations 1990-93, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - United States Government
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare: Intra-Departmental Council on Indian Affairs 1986 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Department of Health and Human Services: "Models That Work" competition 1996 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Department of Labor: Glass Ceiling Commission: focus panel discussion 1995 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Washington Entrepreneurs Group 1987 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - WETV Foundation 1998-2000, undated (Box 38, Folder 10-11)
  - Women's Agenda for the 1990s, Advisory Board, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Working Group on Welfare Reform, Focus Group 1994 (Box 38, Folder 13)
- SERIES V. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Rebecca Adamson
    - Alone undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - With family undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Groups undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - First Nations Development Institute
    - First Nations Arts
      - Miscellaneous undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Buyers' Market of American Craft, Philadelphia 1991-92 (Box 39, Folder 5-6)
      - Photographs of arts for publications, undated
        - Prints (Box 39, Folder 7)
        - Transparencies (Box 39, Folder 8-9)
      - Retail catalog transparencies, Steven Gambaro 1993 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Wholesale catalog transparencies undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Marketing workshop?, Spokane? undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Northwest Coast (marketing?) Workshop, undated
      - Black and white (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Color (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Little Wound School and surrounding area undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Real estate, South Dakota 1994 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Southwestern Association for Indian Arts undated (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Travel undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
- SERIES VI. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
  - Speeches, panels, and roundtables
    - General 1989-2000 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Minnesota Chippewa Tribe Corporate Advisory Committee 3 Aug 1982 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Yale [School of Management?] Tenth Anniversary celebration 14 Nov 1987 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Anatomy of Reservation Economics," Northwest Area Foundation circa 1989 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "The Lakota Fund: A Microenterprise Development Effort," TOES Conference circa 1989 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Washington Comes to Indian Country" Conference, Absentee Shawnee Tribe of Oklahoma Mar 1989 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Ms. Foundation for Women Jun 1990 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - National Association for Science, Technology, and Society Jan 1994 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Bioneers conference Oct 1996 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Banking in Indian Country Conference, U.S. Departments of Justice and Treasury 24 Jul 1997 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "The Growth of Microenterprise and Corporate Social Responsibility," plenary, State of the World Forum 6 Nov 1997 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "Indigenous Economics," Conservation Development Forum, Istanbul 14-18 Nov 1997 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Workshop for Foundation for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Families and Young People 19 Mar 1998 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Inclusive Grantmaking: Building Cultural Competencies for the Next Millennium," Pacific Northwest Grantmakers Forum Conference 17 Sep 1998 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "Ancient Futures," Western Connecticut State University President's Lecture 12 Oct 1998 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - "Explaining a Native Worldview," workshop at Institute of Noetic Sciences 1999 Annual Conference Jul 1999 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Grantmakers of Oregon and Southwest Washington 16 Sep 1999 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Third Civicus World Assembly, Manila, Philippines 21-24 Sep 1999 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Oweesta Conference 1999 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - University for a Night, Synergos 9 May 2000 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Business Women's Network 7th Summit 16 Oct 2000 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - "First Nations and the Future of the Earth," Bioneers Conference 21 Oct 2000 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - United Kingdom Social Investment Forum 31 Oct 2000 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "State of Native America," keynote at Inter-Tribal Native Radio Summit, Portland, Oregon 3 Jun 2001 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Learning for the Future," Business for Social Responsibility Annual Conference 7 Nov 2001 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Writings
    - General 1994-96, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Chapter for Independent Sector book, "Evaluation with Power": correspondence 1995 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Change and Tradition: Native American Philanthrophy Enters a New Era" 1998 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "First Nations and the Future of the Earth," Earth Light: The Magazine of Spiritual Ecology winter 2000-01 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "Investing in Indigenous Knowledge," Akwe:kon Journal summer 1992 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "An Overview of Reservation Economic Development" circa 1989 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Starting at the Center and Working Outward," Winds of Change spring 1989 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Whole Earth Economy," Ms. Sep/Oct 1997 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES
  - 501 (c) 3 nonprofit corporations. 1992 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Indians, general
    - Clippings and miscellaneous 1983-98, undated (Box 41, Folder 12-13)
    - "Celebrating Native American Women" by Diana SteerHoldsworth, draft 1995 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "The Demographics of American Indians: One Percent of the People, Fifty Percent of the Diversity," by Harold L. Hodgkinson, Center for Demographic Policy, Instute for Educational Leadership 1990 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "'May I Help?' The Applied Anthropologist and Indian Self- Determination," paper by Gini Egan-McKenna 1989 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Multicriterion Decision-making in a Tribal Context" by Ronald L. Trosper, draft 1987 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - "The Persistence of Natives," from The Legacy of Conquest: The Unbroken Past of The American West, by Patrician Nelson Limerick undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - "The Predicament of the Native American Leader: A Second Look," by Robert L. Bee, Human Organization, Vol. 49, No. 1, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Abenaki Nation 1991 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture 1986-97 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Aroostook Micmac Council undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Banks and banking 1991-98 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Buffalo 1995-97 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Business plans undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Community-based economic development 1986-97, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Community loan funds and alternative financing
    - General 1985-98 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Center for Community Self Help undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Industrial Cooperative Association Revolving Loan Fund 1985, undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (ICCR) 1984 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Community Reinvestment Act 1993, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Ecological regions of the U.S. 1999, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Economic development
    - General 1984-2000 (Box 42, Folder 14-16)
    - "Economic Development Becomes a Top Priority for Congress in 1987-88," Hopi Epicentre for International Outreach (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - "Financial Assistance for Indian Economic Development Projects," Bureau of Indian Affairs undated (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Impact Evaluation System developed by ACCION International 1986 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - "Report of the Task Force on Indian Economic Development" 1986 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - "Survey of Indian Economic Development Issues" 1983 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Education
    - General 1989-91, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - "Creating a School That Works for Duluth Indian School," report by Education Alternatives Inc. 1990 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Indian Fellowship Program, US Department of Education 1985 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - "Issues in Mathematics Education for Native Americans and Directions for Research," Claudette Bradley, Journal for Research in Mathematics Education 1984 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Liberation of Indian Nations: A Radical Proposal for Change Through Education," paper for graduate school seminar by Elbin Badwound 1987 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Environment
    - General 1991-2001 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Equity Initiative, Office of Solid Waste and Emergency Response, Environmental Protection Agency 1992 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Environmental macroeconomics 1991 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Forestry 1950, 1976, 1992, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Fund-raising 1993-95 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Gaming 2001 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Horse-breeding programs 1995-98 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Indigenous rights 1989 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Laduke, Winona 1995-96 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Land
    - General 1989-97 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "Annual Report of Indian Lands," Bureau of Indian Affairs 1985 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "Heirship: The Indian Amoeba" by Michael L. Lawson 1982 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - "Indian People in Indian Lands 1980: Profiles of American Indian and Alaska Native Populations in Various Settings" by Margaret C. Plantz and Frederick S. Stinson, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Ownership of BIA-managed land undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - "The Politics of Allotment on the Flathead Indian Reservation" by Burton M. Smith 1995 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - "Response to the GAO Report 'Indian Land Ownership Fractionation'" developed by the Indian Land Working Group 1992 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - "Standards for the Preparation of Title Evidence…," U.S. Department of Justice 1970 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Libraries: report of the White House Pre-Conference on Indian Library and Information Services report 1978 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Lumbee Tribe 1941, 1978, 1989-92 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Marketing undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Micro enterprise
    - General 1983-97 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "The Local Economy and Micro-Enterprise Sector of a Native Community: A Case Study of Wikwemikong (Unceded) Indian Reserve #26," research paper by Gord Cunningham 1990 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Native Self-Employment Loan Program/First People's Fund, Canada 1992, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "A Study of Traditional and Informal Sector Micro-Enterprise Activity and Its Impact on the Pine Ridge Reservation Economy," research paper by Richard Sherman 1988 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Mille Lacs Band of Ojibwe undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Native Action 1991-97 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Oneida Tribe of Indians of Wisconsin 1990-96 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Peltier, Leonard 1992 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Philanthropy
    - General 1990-2001 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Native Americans in Philanthropy surveys
      - "Down But Not Out: The Nonprofit Sector in Native America and the New Federalism" 1999 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Grant-giving by American Indian Foundations and Organizations undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - "Options for Giving and the Native American Tradition," discussion paper by James A. Joseph 1996 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Poverty 1985-87, undated (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Program-related investments (PRI) 1993 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Rural programs and projects 1979, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Self-employment 1987-91, undated (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Social investment 1987 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - South and Meso American Indians 1990-93, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Substance abuse 1988, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Sustainability 1992 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Tourism 1988-98, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Government
    - General 1980-94, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "Analysis of American Indian Affairs: Background, Nature, History, Current Issues, Future Trends," Congressional Research Service 1985 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA), Department of the Interior 1981-93, undated (Box 45, Folder 8-9)
    - General Accounting Office
      - Evaluation of the Department of the Interior's High-Level Implementation Plan for improving management of Indian Trust Funds 1999 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Indian Programs: report to the Subcommittee on Interior and related agencies, Committee on Appropriations, U.S. Senate 1999 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - House Committee on Government Operations report, "Misplaced Trust: The Bureau of Indian Affairs' Mismanagement of the Indian Trust Fund" 1992 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Indian Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services 1982-86 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Office of the Special Trustee (OST) for American Indians
      - Summary Presentation of the Strategic Plan 1987 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - Individual Indian Monies Accounts, Approach and Capabilities Overview by Price Waterhouse 1996 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Senate Select Committee on Indian Affairs, survey of tribal economic development 1988 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Virginia 1990-97 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Water rights 1992-96 (Box 45, Folder 18)
- SERIES VIII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS AND COMPUTER MEDIA
  - Videotapes-VHS
    - Becky's interview with Milt Lee [1 tape, 4 copies] (Box 46)
    - Dartmouth Commencement 2004 honorary degree to Rebecca Adamson [1 tape] (Box 46)
    - "First Nations Conf" camera original 11/6/93-11/7/93 [7 tapes] (Box 46)
    - First Nations Sustainable Forestry Fund, Hilo Hawaii, seminar 22 Feb 2002 [3 tapes] (Box 46)
    - FNDI Staff presentation re visits to Kellogg and Mott Foundations Jul 2001 [1 tape] (Box 46)
    - Indigenous Economics 1998 Oweesta Pre-Conference Session [3 tapes, 2 copies of each] (Box 46)
    - Indigenous Economics 15 May 1998, unedited version of the Oweesta Pre-Conference Session [4 tapes] (Box 46)
    - Indigenous Economics Curriculum [1 tape] (Box 46)
    - Infoportrait: Rebecca Adamson, National Film Archive of Philanthropy, interview with R.A., Washington, DC 11 Jan 1996 [1 tape, 3 copies] (Box 46)
    - Rebecca Adamson receiving John W. Gardner Award, Ceremony at Independent Sector Conference 2001 [1 tape] (Box 46)
    - Lending in Indian Country, Federal Reserve Bank of Indianapolis undated [5 tapes] (Box 47)
    - "A Piece of Cloth: The Lakota Fund" undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - Renewing the Promise "final" undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - Social Venture Network Saturday sessions, including RLA plenary undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - Socially Responsible Investing in the Rockies, RLA speech, 1999 Channel 13 news story about Sahnish Farms Cooperative Jul 1996 [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - Speech by Jack Weatherford "Native American Gifts to the World" undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "FNDI Master" unidentified man talking undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Banking Native Americans," Bank of American special training video undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - GWB Lecture, Rebecca Adamson 27 Feb 1997 [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "We Are All Indigenous People" undated [1 tape] may be FNDI production (Box 47)
    - "What Do We Tell Our Children?" undated [1 tape] may be FNDI production (Box 47)
    - The Native Self-Employment Loan Fund, Calmeadow [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "The New Capitalists: Economics in Indian Country" [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Focus on Women" with Florence Rapoport, guest: Rebecca Adamson 30 Aug 1996 [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - Lakota Fund 4/10/86 [2 tapes] (Box 47)
    - Lakota Fund 3/19/86 [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - Lakota Fund 1/28-1/30/86 [6 tapes] (Box 47)
    - Lakota Fund 2/18/86 [2 tapes] (Box 47)
    - "Belsu National Park, First Nations in Meehdurechensk, Dave's Excursion to Belsu, NTSC" undated partly in Russian? [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Spirit: The Seventh Fire," promotional video for a stage show of American Indian music and dance undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Reuben Snake Video, Complements of Gary Rhine, KIFARU Productions," miscellaneous footage of Reuben Snake, Nebraska Winnebago, some is 1993 [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Eagle Staff Grant, Regenerating our Past-Traditional Practices and Community Gardens, Chemehueyi Indian Tribe" Feb 2001 [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Developing a Native American Entrepreneurship Curriculum: Thoughts From Montana," aimed at Tribal College, Rebecca Adamson included undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Creating the Future: Community-Based Economic Development" Produced by Juniroa Productions, Inc. for the Office of Hawaiian Affairs undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
    - "Chief Wilma P. Mankiller: Woman of Power" directed by Mary Scott, Roeper Scott Video Productions 1992 (Box 47)
  - Videotapes-Beta: "We Are All Indigenous People" undated [1 tape] (Box 47)
  - Videotapes--U-Matic: Renewing the Promise undated (Box 47)
  - Computer disks
    - 73, 5 ¼" disks, First Nations Development Institute files (Box 48)
    - 30, 3 ½" disks (Box 48)
  - Compact disks
    - Scans of photographs of Neva and Rebecca Adamson [1 cd] (Box 48)
    - Scans of 4 photos by Eric Haase (possibly for First Nations Arts?) [1 cd] (Box 48)
  - Digital video disks
    - "American Indian Millennium: Renewing Our Ways of Life for FutureGenerations," curriculum produced by LifeWay: A Resource for the Continuation of Native LifeWays, participants include Katsi Cook, Jose Barreiro, Tonya Gonnella Frischner, Sherry Salway Black, etc. [2 DVDs with accompanying print material 1998 (Box 48)
  - Audiocassettes
    - Rebecca Adamson interviewed by Dierdre Blake on Fredericksburg, VA, radio program "Focus" 3 Mar 2002 [1 cassette, 2 copies] (Box 48)
    - Collaborative Leadership in Action Round Table Audio Series, session at Le Chateau Montebello, Montebello, Quebec, Rebecca Adamson a participant 26-30 Oct 1997 [13 cassettes] (Box 48)
- SERIES IX. ARTIFACTS AND MEMORABILIA
  - 365 Days of Women calendar, 1995 [Rebecca Adamson is May 26] (Box 49)
  - Wrapper for Morongo Sovereignty [chocolate] Bar, Morongo Band of Mission Indians, Banning, California (Box 49)
  - "Native American Rulers" ruler by Rich Frog Industries, Burlington, Vermont undated (Box 49)
  - Sweet grass braids (Box 49)
  - Leather and beadwork (Box 49)
  - Stick with fur, beadwork, and leather (Box 49)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
    - Clippings re Rebecca Adamson (photocopies of these are in box 1) (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
    - First Nations Development Institute
      - Field Operations
        - Oglala Sioux Tribe:
          - Brotherhood Community Health Clinic/Porcupine Clinic, flow chart circa 1986 (Box 50, Folder 2)
          - Artwork by John Iron Moccasin, Little Wound School, 7th grade circa 1983 (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe of Michigan: oversize materials from "An Economic Development Plant for the Saginaw Chippewa Community, Mount Pleasant, Michigan," James M. Murray and Charles F. Wheelock undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Publications: original artwork, layouts, and stats 1982, undated (Box 50, Folder 5-9)
  - IV. ORGANIZATIONS
    - Conservation Development Forum: Forum newsletter, Issue No. 1, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Little Wound School: The Mustang News, Little Wound School, Kyle, South Dakota: Mar-Apr 1980, Jan-Feb 1981, Mar-Apr 1981 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - National Center for American Indian Enterprise Development, Mississippi Band of Choctaw Indians publications 1989, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Seventh Generation Fund: newsletter, Native Self-Sufficiency, Vol 8, No. 3, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - VI. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
    - Yale School of Management 10th Anniversary newsletter Jan 1987; Western Connecticut State University President's Lecture Series posters, 1998 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - VII. SUBJECT FILES
    - Sault Ste. Marie Tribe of Chippewa Indians: Win Awenen Nisitotung, "He Who Understands," newsletter, Vol. 8, No. 1, Jan 1986 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Posters and bumper sticker 1988, undated (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - "Indigenous economics" definition and artwork (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - First Nations Development Institute: First Nations Arts banner (Map-case Flat file)
  - Chart of Ratifications of International Labour Conventions 1 Jan 1989 (Map-case Flat file)
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES--RESTRICTED MATERIALS
  - First Nations Development Institute
    - Loans by Lakota Fund
      - Loretta Cook, Cook and Co. 1987 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Richard and Mona Hagen, bingo gaming room and concessions 1987 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Lucy Bernice Little, gas station 1990 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Dale McGaa, Crazy Horse Construction 1987 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Steve Reddy, S/K Automotive Service 1987-88 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Floyd White Eyes and Martin Red Bear, Lakota Image 1987 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Don Pourier, Don's Pest and Weed Control 1989 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Dean Steele, coin operated tire inflators 1989 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Dean Janis, hair salon 1992 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Madeline Terry, hair salon and flower shop 1992 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Patty Ward, food vending 1992 (Box 51, Folder 11)